Okay, so let's go ahead and move through,
好的 我们继续
step by step and talk about the LookAway node.
我们逐步学习 LookAway 节点
The imported modules are similar to those in simple arm,
导入的模块与简单机器臂类似
except this time we have
但是这次 我们
the image message type being imported so that the camera data can be used.
正在导入图像信息类型 以便使用摄像机数据
Here, we define a class for this node to better keep track of
在这里 我们为这个节点定义一个类 来更好地跟踪
the robot arms current movement state and position history.
机器人臂当前的运动状态和位置历史
Just as in the node definitions before,
就像之前的节点定义一样
the node is initialized using the rospy.init_node function.
该节点使用 rospy.init_node 函数进行初始化
And at the end of the method,
在本方法的末尾
rospy.spin is used to block until a shutdown request is received by the node.
使用 rospy.spin 进行阻塞 直到节点收到关闭请求
The first subscriber, self.sub1,
第一个订阅者 self.sub1
subscribes to the simple_arm/joint_states topic.
订阅 simple_arm/joint_states 主题
The node is written to check the camera only when the arm is not moving.
只有当机器臂没有移动时 才会写入节点 检查摄像机
And by subscribing to simple_arm/joint_state,
通过订阅 simple_arm/joint_state
changes in the position of the arm can be tracked.
可以跟踪机器臂位置的变化
The message type for this topic is joint_state and with each message,
这个主题的消息类型是 joint_state 伴随着每条消息
the message data is passed to the joint_states_callback function.
消息数据都会被传递给 joint_states_callback 函数
The second subscriber, self.sub2,
第二个订阅者 self.sub2
subscribes to the rgb_camera/image _raw topic.
订阅 rgb_camera/image _raw 主题
The message type here is image and with each message,
这里的消息类型是图像 伴随着每条消息
the look_away_callback function is called.
Look_away_callback 函数都会被调用
A service proxy is how rospy enables calling a service from a node.
通过服务代理 rospy 可以从节点调用服务
The service proxy here is created using the name of the service you wish to call,
此处的服务代理是使用你希望调用的服务的名称
along with the service class definition.
以及服务类定义创建的
In this case, arm_mover/safe_move, and go to position.
在本例中 arm_mover/safe_move 然后 GoToPosition
The actual calls to the service will take place in the look_away_callback method.
实际的服务调用将发生在 look_away_callback 方法中
There are two helpers defined in the code,
代码中定义了两个助手
uniform underscore image, and coord underscore equa.l.
uniform_image 以及 coord_equal
The uniform_image method takes an image as input and checks if
Uniform_image 方法将图像作为输入 并检查是否
all color values in the image are the same as the color value as the first pixel.
图像中的所有颜色值与第一个像素的颜色值相同
This essentially checks that all color values in the image are the same.
它会检查图像中的所有颜色值是否都相同
The coord_equal method returns true if the coordinates coord_1
如果坐标 coord_1 和 coord_2 的分量相同 满足规定公差
and coord_2 have equal components up to the specified tolerance.
则 coord_equal 方法返回 true
When self.sub1 receives a message on the simple_arm/joint _states topic,
当 self.sub1 在 simple_arm/joint _states 主题上收到消息时
the message is passed to the joint_states_callback in the variable data.
该消息被传递给变量数据中的 joint_states_callback
The joint_states_callback uses the coord_equal helper function to check if
Joint_states_callback 使用 coord_equal 帮助函数检查
the current joint_states provided in data are the same as the previous joint_states,
数据中提供的当前 joint_states 与之前的 joint_states 是否相同
which are stored in self.last_position.
它们存储在 self.last_position 中
If the current and previous joint_states are the same,
如果当前和之前的 joint_states 相同
up to the specified tolerance,
满足规定公差
then the arm has stopped moving.
则机器臂已经停止移动
So, the self.arm_moving flag is set to false.
所以 self.arm_moving 标志被设置为 false
If the current and previous joint_states are different,
如果当前和之前的 joint_states 不同
the arm is still moving.
那么机器臂仍在移动
In this case, the method updates self.last_position with
这时 该方法使用当前位置数据
current position data and sets self.arm_moving to true.
更新 self.last_position 并将 self.arm_moving 设置为 true
The look_away_ callback is receiving data from the rgb_camera/image_raw topic.
Look_away_callback 正在接收来自 rgb_camera/image_raw 主题的数据
The first line of this method verifies that the arm is not moving and also checks
该方法的第一行验证手臂没有移动 同时检查
if the image is uniform.
图像是否均匀
If the arm isn't moving and the image is uniform,
如果手臂不在移动 并且图像均匀
then GoToPositionRequest message is created and sent using the safe_move service,
则创建 GoToPositionRequest 消息并使用 safe_move 服务发送该消息
moving both joint angles to 1.57.
将两个关节角度调整至 1.57
The method also logs a message warning you that the camera has detected
该方法还会记录一条消息 警告你相机已检测到
a uniform image along with the elapsed time to return a nicer.
一个均匀的图像 随着时间的推移 会返回一个更好的图像